MOHD. SAZID KHAN

Counselling Psychologist and career counsellor

Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh | +91 9140620857 | Saz786khan@gmail.com

SUMMARY

I am a counselling psychologist and certified career counsellor with over 2 years and 8 months of experience. I specialise in facilitating adults and children's emotional, behavioral, and career problems. I have counselled over 1000 clients, including adults and children, addressing issues such as anxiety, depression, stress, and career indecision, increasing overall client mental well-being by 80%.

EDUCATION

Amity University Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh Masters of Arts in Counselling Psychology 2021 - 2023

WORK EXPERIENCE

Career Counsellor | Medhavi Professional Services Pvt. Ltd. (iDreamCareer) Oct 2024 - Nov 2024

- Provided personalized career counselling and psychometric assessments for students.
- Guided students in stream selection, higher education, and study abroad opportunities.
- Managed physical and remote sessions with proper documentation and reporting.

Counselling psychologist | Career counsellor, Sukoonya Enterprises LLP May 2024- Present

- Facilitating counselling and therapy sessions, taking career counselling sessions along with assessment, Created content that enhanced social media presence, resulting in a 50% increase in engagement.
- Facilitating 10 workshops and internships, and increasing participant knowledge retention by 35%.

Career counsellor | Medhavi Professional Services Pvt. Ltd. (iDreamCareer) January 2024- Present

- Provided comprehensive career guidance to over 50 students and professionals, achieving a 90% improvement in career goal clarity.
- Skilled in career assessment, personalized counselling, and career planning, helping clients set and achieve career goals.

Consultant Psychologist | YourDOST Health Solutions Pvt Ltd November 2024 - Present

- Deliver counselling and mentorship to student trainees.
- Conduct in-person and telephonic sessions to support learner development.
- Maintain detailed records using Salesforce.
- Participate in project reviews and development meetings.

- Conducted counselling and therapy sessions, created engaging content, and facilitated 15 workshops and internships, increasing participant knowledge retention by 50%
- I also spearheaded a revamp of the company messaging to better align with customer needs, which resulted in a 25% increase in lead conversion rates and a 10% improvement in customer loyalty within six months. My efforts contributed to enhanced client engagement and more effective therapeutic outcomes.

MOHD. SAZID KHAN

Counselling Psychologist and career counsellor

Lucknow, Uttar Pradesh | +91 9140620857 | Saz786khan@gmail.com

WORK EXPERIENCE

Mentor/Counsellor, Generation India

August 2023 - October 2024

 Orchestrated comprehensive mentorship sessions, ensuring participants acquired job search skills and confidence, resulting in a 40% higher job placement rate.

Subject Matter expert, UpThink

May 2024 - June 2024

 Developed and curated a comprehensive set of 700+ MCQs for a psychology module, ensuring accuracy and relevance.

Career counsellor, IDream careers

April 2024 - May 2024

- Conducted career counseling sessions for over 100 students in 10th and 12th grades.
- Created detailed synopses for each student based on session information, providing personalized and effective guidance.
- Assisted students in selecting the best career paths tailored to their strengths and requirements, resulting in a 40% increase in career decision confidence.

SKILLS

- · Counselling and Therapy
- Psychotherapy
- Solution-focused therapy
- · Relationship therapy
- Career counselling

- Career Assessment and Planning
- · Health and wellness coaching
- Mentorship
- Mindfulness Techniques

ADDITIONAL CERTIFICATIONS AND MEMBERSHIPS

Career Counselling (Level 1 and level 2)

- IDream Careers (2023)
- 90 Hours of training and practice.

NLP Practitioner and NLP Master Practitioner

• Complimentary Therapists accredited association (CTAA) and The Priority Academy (2024)

Certified POSH Consultant (Feeling Minds | August 2024)

 Successfully completed a two-day online workshop on The Sexual Harassment of Women at Workplace (Prevention, Prohibition, and Redressal) Act, 2013.

World Health Organization (WHO) Fides Community Member (September 2024-Present)

• Collaborate with global health professionals to contribute to discussions on public health initiatives.

PUBLICATIONS

- Effect of Pornography on Romantic relationships, Quality of life and Well-being (IJIRSET)
- Chakras and Human Body (PSYCHLETTER AIBAS)